Welcome back to
class, and now we're
going to learn a few more parts of L, and
now we'll begin.
Don't forget we're already
in the middle of Chi's perfection,
and we've reached the end
of the effort of K's joy,
and we'll complete it in about
14 years of work.
Now we're talking about types of giving
alms. The acts of giving that are
n't good
here are like giving away
alcohol, for example,
here, for example, wishing. Here, it means it, it, it, it
's a
Hindu tradition, and it's like killing a
beetle. V, here, it's one
of the parts that he said
means a wrong idea, and there are
many stories. Here, there are
people who give
offerings, offering
cows,
and then he also has
names of  The bad attitudes
when you give alms are when
you try to do
good things, your mind must
be in a
wonderful, good state. When
you give money or contribute to a
project like building a road, for example, you
need to avoid
attitudes like
giving with a sense of
obligation.
The second thing is that I'm
trying to do it, it's called
self-struggle. "Praise"
means I hope people will
find out that I'm giving away a
large portion of my money, and you know,
people will be impressed by what
I'm doing. The next thing
means "
I hope people hear about
how wonderful the things I've done are." And the next thing
means...  Disappointment is
like you
should be in a state of
not being very happy while you are giving
you should be happy
and I hope everyone the
next word
this word is very important
it means
like she said she said so she said
everyone is very excited
She said that and I
also like I am very
excited and I gave too much I gave too much
it happens and
sometimes you give You feel like
you give you feel very
excited and then you promise too much
and like I
promise I will build a cabin or
something and then I
think about it and it's like it's very
important so that you don't
regret it just be quiet and
just give in
English it could be the
second part like
you when you do something
wrong  Maybe I did something
right, or maybe just stay silent and do
it and be happy with it.
Try to control yourself.
Wait for me. It means I will help
my friend, but I won't help
other people. It
means you
help the people you
like and you don't help the people
you don't
like. In my country,
every year they decide they go to
another country. They hate another country and know that
you are 7 or 71 years old, and you realize that you
have to find something like
your rival. Your enemy has to
change after 10 years. And they
go to different countries and
they say that those are
bad people, and then they are
bad people. Not all of them are
good people, and this year they find bad people, and then
their rival, their enemy, of
this year, and then it changes again.
That's how it is. It changes
every year, year after year, and then
everyone says that people
in this country are bad, that Germans are bad, that
Russians are bad. Every time I hear that,
I try to go
to that country. So I went to
Morocco, I spent two months
there practicing meditation, two months in a religious retreat, in
a village. I learned Polish,
and there was a
very big rival, a very big enemy
of America. And we became friends.
They were very good people, and I
had a wonderful time.
I even learned Arabic,
but I forgot so much, I
forgot more than what you would
learn. So you know that
enemies change every year, and whether
you believe it or not, you
have to forget about it. Forget what
I told you. Make
friends with everyone, everyone.
It's all the same, and everyone wants to
be friends with you, so
be friends with everyone, and
be generous with them. Be able to
tell everyone that I am friends with everyone
in the world and
I love every country. People ask me
what my country is, and I say
I live in New York, and I've visited
Muslim countries. And they
dropped bombs, and then they said, "Where are you
from?" and I said, "I'm from
Manhattan," and they said, "Mahattan," and I
said, "It's a country of America,"
and everyone is fine.
You have to get used to it. When you
travel, you
'll find that people are all the same,
everyone has a very sweet spot in
every place. And if you
talk to
them now, the next picture
is this, it's very interesting when
I hear about those things. Oh my god,
people usually buy
white tennis shoes and...  They
try to keep it white, keep it
white like that, and I think that
everything is actually very personal to me. They
buy white tennis shoes,
and
I don't have time to find
my shoes, but so, so there
's a
very interesting idea here, which is
when people finish it. He
finishes that, he finishes the part
of the perfection of giving, and
he has a very great part
here. I think this is a great part.
When he leads a sentence
in his book, in a
famous book, he has written two books, let's
call it the
Bodhicitta book, the
path of life, and he
also wrote another book, and
all these ideas come
from ancient scriptures, so
I always want to teach
you because I think the
guidance in this is very,
very great, and
[sound]  [Music]
It has secrets here, so
I... I actually worked with
those things, and recently I
decided there's a reason why it's not
famous.
I hate to say
this, but I should. By the
way, it's not
what you wrote here; it's just a
collection of quotes from
different books. I know it's not
your book,
but there are books of yours that are
more famous. There's a famous book
I once wrote about, but it's
a part of it. It's a book that
collects famous quotes, and it's very
long, and I stopped working
with that book. And you led me to a
quote here. You talked about
something about giving,
charity, that you need to know, it's
amazing. Here, it's everything
you have, you possess right now,
even your body.  The
position of your possessions,
your time, when you become a
Bodhisattva, everything is
sold. Even your body, even
your white shoes, your house,
your money—
to me, it's
something very precious. Everything
you possess when you become a
Bodhisattva, you must promise, you promised, that you
will give it away. So now it's no
longer yours. You just take care of
all those things until you
finish giving. Do you understand
what I'm saying? Everything
you possess has truly been
dedicated, given to all
others, even your time,
your body, you
offer it,
you give it away. You offer it, like
a servant, to
all sentient beings, because you
no longer possess it. You are
like a person, a person
sharing the giving. You are holding
it temporarily.  Okay, but until
you transfer it to everyone
else, you understand what I mean? You're
like you're in an
Amazon warehouse. You don't own
anything; in Amazon, it's just
a warehouse. Until they
transfer it away, even your body,
your time, even if
you're a Bodhisattva, you
commit to giving it away to everyone
else. You just take care of them. You take
care of them until they're put on
a boat and it's
transferred away. Now I want your money,
I want your house, I want your time.
And now, the Buddha said that when
everything is in the
warehouse, you have to take responsibility for taking
good care of it. It doesn't need to be
yours anymore. When you receive the
Bodhisattva vow, all your money,
all your belongings, all
your time, and even your body,
it's truly given away, given away, and
it's fortunate that...  It hasn't been
delivered yet, it hasn't been
shipped, but you can't
mess with your body
before it's shipped. It's not all
yours anymore, you don't have it anymore, it
depends on everything, it belongs to
other people. You have to live a healthy life.
You have to be
healthy, that's your responsibility because
it's no longer your body. I
think that's a very
beautiful idea. It's like when you say, "Teacher,
when you have a shirt, a pen,
there's a button on my stomach,
it's undone, and I don't know
how it came undone.
The button on my stomach is
undone, and I don't know
why." You can't gain
weight because it will make you sick. You can't
gain weight, you
have to take care of your body, you have to go
to the Dream Room. You have to do yoga,
you have to eat more wisely
because it's no longer your body.
It doesn't belong to you anymore,
you're just temporarily taking care of it,
you're taking care of the things in
that warehouse until the Thy,
that shipping, arrives. So that's a
very dead commitment,
a very wonderful thing, and that's what it is
every day, ending the
first perfection,
what you call... You don't have the right to
gain weight, you don't have the right to sleep,
you don't have the right to just take care of
yourself because you don't
own this body. You commit to
giving it away, meaning
you should join a
good club, a good reading club.
I think that club is
one of the great ideas
we've ever had. You
commit to about 10 hours, like about
900 to 10
hours. I had about
10, he came to my house and he took my
computer and
my phone and I found...  I woke up
at 2:00 AM and I went around
my house and I said, "Oh, where's my computer?
Where's my phone?" and
I started looking
everywhere. Then I said, "Maybe it's
not a problem anymore, but, but,
but when you join the
book club, you'll find
things, information, information that...
I, I, I wondered why
my fingernails grow faster than
my toenails. For example,
you should go to the
Good Night book club at 10:00
PM. We have something very
special. If that's the case,
I, I, I often give it to my wife.
Sometimes, sometimes when my wife has
another house, I have to take care of
her house, and
when she comes home, she sits
on the bed, and I, I only
have her. She gives me a
tap.
When you get a physical book,
when you order that book,
it's also a...  The book that was translated,
you should keep a copy at
bedtime, around 10
o'clock, open it up.
I believe you will fall asleep
in just 2 minutes. It's very difficult, but you will
sleep very soundly and deeply. It's very good
for sleep. Incidentally, I
want you to read
that book; it will help you fall asleep in 2 minutes.
Please, please, please, please stay away
from your computer, and you will
find something. For example, when you are in a hotel room, please ...
In the evening, I never
sleep 8 hours, not 8 hours in
my life. Now I sleep
8:00, like a baby. Because I
know that at 10:00 I'm like I'm going to
sleep, and then at 6:00 I start to get
up. I start working at 6:05
and I don't give any meetings
until 11:00. I work for
about 5 hours and I think it's
great. If you come here and let
me teach you
something, it's the best thing
I can teach you.
Join Good Night. The
Good
Night reading club, its short name is
Night Club. It's a club, maybe
in this context it
's a Night Club, but this is the
best thing I can offer
you. And don't wait, don't wait until
you feel ready, don't wait until you do it.
Do it right now because it will help
you work more efficiently, your mind
will be happier and clearer,
you will be more settled, you will be better at reading
books, and you will feel that you will teach and
you will be settled for 5 minutes, 10 minutes, but
your life will change, your whole
life will change, and you will learn
something new. This is Good Night
Book Club. This is the advice of
Stia to take care of the things that
you have not yet transferred to
other beings. This is
advice that has three to four
parts, four parts in three different groups.
It is 12, it is a total of 12 numbers. You
have committed your body to
others. You promise that you
will receive the Bodhisattva precepts. You say that
you will serve, just
like I commit to serving
everyone. I give away
this body, so it is no longer
your body. It is a
very
big commitment, and then your whole thing.  I
'll go to the Amazon warehouse
first. Always remind yourself that you
've
committed all your things to
others. You've truly committed
to
those things. This is very
important until the time you're
ready to
move. It's about your rhythm, about
taking care of your own body and not letting
it get hurt. Don't overeat, don't overwork, don't say it's not
your body anymore. You promised
it to others, and
you have to take care of it. It's like me,
I have a problem with taking care of
myself for selfish
reasons. Do you understand what I mean?
I'm not a
good person, but I have
problems when my wife says, "You have to take
good care of your body," but you
have to be like me, you have to eat
fruits and vegetables, for
example. I've done so much, and
it hurts me, it hurts me.
But I... but it's like...  It's like,
but you're hurting
other people because it's no longer yours.
It's not like that,
this body isn't mine. It's like
I'm borrowing something,
like borrowing someone
else's car, and then breaking it. It's
like Stanley is on the road and
he's not waiting for me, but
he has to do everything for me, and
then that car still goes to the
hospital, and then two months later, you see,
everything. You don't want to hurt
other people, other people's things,
so you
can do things like, don't hurt
your own body. Don't eat too much sugar,
don't drink too much coffee, you ca
n't sleep at night, don't get
busy with nonsense,
and all of that. Protect
your body because it's
your responsibility to take care of
your own body because you have to have a long
life, a long life, it will
be millions of years.  It took
millions of years for you to be in
this room. You have to take care of that person.
That person is very valuable.
I don't care
who you are, but you are one of
10 million people, you are one of the people
here. You are in
this room for millions of years,
working hard. Don't
waste it, don't hurt it. You have to
have a responsibility to
sleep well, eat well, eat well, eat well, eat in a
healthier way. Don't work
too
much, play music
sometime, play rock and
roll. You have to relax, you have to
feel happy because it's very important. You have to feel happy.
People often say things like, "It's like, 'Teacher, I
don't have time to see you,'
but I have time to play
rock and roll. I say, 'I have to have time to have
fun, I can't see other people.' And don't
let your body
do bad things, don't hurt your body.
Don't do that to your body,
and it, and what he means here is,
always keep your shoes clean.
It means you have
shoes, and if they get dirty,
you have to clean them. So you are
here. You have your body. You have your
time, but you have to take
good care of it. If you
hurt yourself, and you
hurt yourself, then you have to take care of
yourself.
Throughout my whole life,
I've never had a doctor
for many years, so
you have to take good care of yourself.
You have to find a
good doctor for you. You have to have time,
you have to have meetings with doctors
and take care of your health
because you have to take care of yourself to
live a long
life.
You are ready to give, just to be given away. Take
good care of it, don't take good care of
it, and don't make it  It was lifted up, and
you should keep it safe.  Be pure,
be clean, and keep
your heart pure. Then
he spoke
about the future, about having
responsibility for this in
the next life. This is something
very serious here,
like him, like Master G, has
a problem with taking care of
his body, but now I want to
take better care of it,
even if I have
n't been born yet. So the
answer is yes, you have
a future, you have to be
responsible for taking care of your future,
even if you haven't seen it yet.
But when you have to, you have to accumulate
good karma, and then it will be
beneficial, you will have a good body in
your next life. Because if
you only take care of
the body you were born with, then
it is no
longer yours, but
your body in the future is already committed.
You have to
You have a responsibility to collect
good karma to create a
good body for your future life.
It's a very interesting game, and I
think that, like, I will try to be
more generous because I promised
that in my
next life, because I want more
money, I will take care of the poor,
the hungry, I will take care of the homeless,
I will take care of those who
are in war.
Because I want my next body
in my next life to be a
beautiful, good body, and because I
promised those things, because it's like
a promise to
yourself, a gift for
your birthday. So, He said to
be ready to give, to
protect your body, and
to keep it in a beautiful form,
your future body. So
in the book, He only mentions eight
things in the future that you,
your body, you should...  Get ready for it! There are eight
qualities about your future body
that you should start preparing for right
now. You have to give away, give
away a
next living body. Right now,
what you do right now is to sow the
seeds for
your future life. So, by the way,
it's quite interesting to think about
it. It's wonderful to think about not being
selfish anymore, isn't it? It's
not just you; you have to take care of
your body, you have to take care of your
future money.
Then
you need to take care of
your next body because you have to give it away,
and you can't give
away the noisy things.
You have to give away the
wonderful things, the ordinary things.
So when I think about
it, I feel, oh, it's wonderful!
My next body! So I say,
oh, tell me, what do I have to
do next? Okay, this is...  Eight things, so
it's not just in Lam, but by Mr.
San, and like a writer about
Land
Dream, I guess you already know
that you already
know me, I've searched in the
data archive and there are eight things. The first is to
protect life and help people
in this life to have a
body that lives well. The
first thing is to
collect the things that will give you a
body in the future. You will have, it's
like buying a new car.
You wouldn't buy a
new car that
will break down after the first 100 miles.
You want it to go about 400
miles, a car that will go about 400,000 miles. In the
next part, collect the
things that will give you a car that will run
400,000 miles in the
future. The second is to be
patient, don't get
angry. It's like you will...  What do we do with
the next body we always want?
We want to be attractive, we want to be
attractive. It's not selfish,
what would you call it?
It's a very real thing. If
you look beautiful, many people will
come to your class. That's a
very serious thing. In
Buddhism, Atisa said, "
I am happy because I was born
a beautiful person." Because
all the Tibetan people
came to my class. So,
he said that's the
karma you should prepare for
your next body. It means not getting angry, not getting angry,
not getting angry, because you
will think the same as
you. I
have committed to
my next body, and
I have committed to it. It must definitely
be a
very
beautiful person. So here, it means being
generous in your next life
when you are born into a new life.
In a country where you're
born, it's very
helpful. It's very helpful if
you're born in a country where you have money, and if
you're born in a
poor country, you have the resources to
help others, right?
So now I'm not saying you're
a bad person, you're a good person, but
you're like someone who
builds roads here, the
road builders here, it's
a good thing for
their rebirth.
You need a car, or you need
a new car on a
new road, right? Now,
get a new car, but
get a new truck
[music].
When the teacher calls for building a
place, it's about $200,000. But
it actually cost millions of
dollars, about five times that, but it's a very
great place.
But be generous, it's
a good thing to have a place.  A
beautiful body in your life is
when you have money and you live in a
country that also has money, then
you can help more people.
If you are a bad person, you don't
have money. I don't mean
that. But you should
try, try to give away a lot of
money. Give, give away
whatever you can. It's the
same thing: you have $10 and you give away a lot.
You will have a result, like
someone building a center for
students. You give away everything
you can, everything
you have, but without
hurting even your own family
or yourself. You have
convenient conditions like
having a house, enough to live in, enough
food to eat. Give away as
much as you can and you still feel comfortable. The
next thing is to share your resources.
Share any resources you have
with others, just like you.
Whether you are the leader of the Diamond Kingdom or the leader of the demon Al, the
ancient book demon, share your
resources with
others, whatever responsibility you have.
Whatever position you hold, share it. Be
generous with
your resources; share them with
others, just as you would with someone who has a
responsibility. If you give it
away, give them the opportunity to be
a leader or
a boss. If you are a
leader or a
boss, it's
a way to be a
good boss.
Share that power, share
your position. Don't be greedy. Share
it, and in
your next life, your future life, your
fourth life, you will
have
good fortune.
Always keep your promises. Always keep your promises.
When you say something,
remember it. Always keep your
promise.  Don't forget your promise. I
think your promise is that in
50 minutes you remember what you promised.
When you set out to do
something, there's a recording device
inside your consciousness.
It's like always remembering the
recording device in your consciousness, or
keeping it on your phone –
a list of what you
promised. Keep your word. Keep your word,
don't break it,
but don't promise
easily. Because when you promise, you must keep
it, and then in
your future life, people will
always believe in you, people will always
listen to you. Because it's amazing to
collect karma. It
really took me a
very long time to find and
collect that karma,
but I must say it's very
interesting. It's like
someone always keeping their word. You
should have a
name.  The voice in
your next life, you have to take care of
other people's problems or other people's mistakes.
Don't waste time, take care of
other people. Don't
waste time. Everyone has problems,
and we all have problems. We all have
bad habits.
Everyone.
If everyone in this world
is pretending they don't have any bad habits, then
they are pretending they don't have
any bad habits
because you wouldn't have come to
this world unless you had
bad habits. So someone said, "I am
pure, I am pure, like
snow," and I said, "No, you are not
like that." They asked why, and
I said, "Because you are here, you are in
this world, this is
behind that classroom,
this world, we are all the
same. We all have
problems, so don't waste time."  Instead of wasting your time,
make mental lists
of the
bad things about
other people. Pay attention to the parts
of yourself that you have a lot to
do; you don't need to add
more. Then you also have
your bad parts, your bad habits, but
you prepare for a beautiful body
in the future.
That body might become
famous. You can use
that fame to your advantage.
You might hurt
your true self, but try to become
famous. Because when you become famous,
you can use that fame to
your advantage. You will know how to use it in a
useful way. Number
seven: Each person has a
different social level, and each country is
different. You know that
each country in
this world is
not just a
world, but like a
higher community.  Your friend, you're in a
taller person, like, "Oh, look, she's
so beautiful, but she has very strange ears,
this world is like
that,
we have very
strange things, so we need to be a
good person. So there's something that
in
our next life,
maybe we can be reborn.
With me, I have a vision for
myself, that I can
design, that's me, I look forward. And
I have a person that I will become, they
should be a person who is
respected by their community. I mean,
I'm trying to be
different. So in some
communities, if you talk a
lot, and you're respected, but
in some communities, you don't
talk, but
you, because there are different issues.
So every country is different, so
try to have
your karma so that you can be born in the
next life where people will talk."
Oh, this person is really
beautiful, so you should try to collect good
karma for
those things. Have good karma
so that you can have an extremely
healthy body and a long life.
Number one is that we want a
long life, but number eight is
about a body with
many good qualities. A
healthy body is important, but if you live
a long life without good health, that's
not right, is it?
So, living a long life isn't enough;
you also need a healthy body.
You need to build
temples, you need to build
things, you can learn a lot of languages,
and you need a body like that.
So, the
nickname to
get good karma
for all eight of these things is
what? The teacher is giving away 100 dollars to whoever answers correctly.
One person answered: "It's the
enjoyment of effort."
If I have three... (unclear text)  If the words are
n't good, I
'll throw this bet away.
Show this picture, show this
picture, the last picture,
draw Vy, draw
your shoes. Don't forget
this image, this image is about taking
care of your body in
this life and taking care of your body in the
next life. Take care of
these shoes to become a person, a
crazy person, someone who sprays
your shoes, white shoes one
morning, because you won't have that body
anymore, those shoes aren't yours anymore, they
belong to other people. So you
have to take care of the body that you don't have,
you don't yet own it. That's
your responsibility.
I think life will be
more complicated, but again,
I also have problems
taking care of my body, but
I have to take care of it because it's
for other people, and it's like, like,
my boss used to call me when I worked
in New York, and he used to call me and
He told me that we have a
very large order here,
about 10,000 rings, and tomorrow,
and you have to work part-
time, you can't go home, and
then
he said, "I can't do it,
I'm leaving," and he said, "
I'm going to fire you," and I said, "
And he said, 'Get out of here,'
and then after 6 months, he
said, "But
he called me to his office," and he said, "
You're the first one.
Without you, we're
nothing, we can't do anything.
When you're here, we know
what we need to do, but
when you're not here, we've
failed. You have to help us, sir.
We have a very large order from
tomorrow. You're a great person," and I
said, "
Yeah, if you tell me to give it to
others, I'll do it. I feel
like I'll do
it. I'll eat vegetables. I'm one of
the students."
My future student, I
will eat it. It makes me, I will eat vegetables. It's like,
if you tell me that it's
for the benefit of everyone else,
I have to eat the spinach portions
of
my teacher. You can do
that now.
The teacher is asking if he has
time. We'll talk for another 5 minutes. We
'll finish this point because we're going
to the next part, the
first part. And when Nga
Nga talks about the part that
applies to the first part,
that's your body. First,
you have to take care of your body for
others, and then you take care of
your future body,
like your car. That's a
very good idea. You have to take care of
your car, your car, because it's
no longer your own,
you're borrowing it. You're driving a
car. You're driving a car that you
've given to the people who gave it to you.  To
other people. And they haven't
received that car yet. They have
n't received it, so it's no longer
your car. So you have to take
good care of your things. You have to
take care of them. I
hate taking care of cars
that only run 5,000 miles and then stop. I
hate that, and I never
do
that. You are very special people,
and someone has to take care of
their car. Why? Because you have to
take other people
to the hospital or something. You
have a responsibility to take care of
your own things because you
need to serve other people
because it's no longer yours.
You have to take good care of your house. Take
good care of your house. Keep it clean of
rubbish. Because when you die,
you lose someone who comes and cleans it up.
It feels very
unpleasant, frustrating, like when a friend
dies and then you come home.  of
theirs and like, oh my god, 6 working days
here, always keep your house
clean and don't keep a lot of trash in your house,
keep your life clean, it's
like you're going to die tomorrow,
don't let other people come and
clean up your trash, get rid of
that trash out of your life, it's
like me, me, me, I take all my trash, I put it in the trash bag, then I go to sleep at 10, and at 10:30 I
wake up and go.
Dispose of trash like you guys, ...
Your body, which you can use
in the following week, is
something you
lose in
America
[music]. Take
good care of those things.
Sa means take care of
your possessions.
Don't keep
things in your house because
you might get robbed or
bad people might do something to you. But
your possessions should
be clean. Always keep them clean.
It's a very interesting idea.
Don't cheat others to get
things. Because when you die,
those things will be given to
other people and they will be
dirty. So don't take dirty
things from others.
Your things should
be
clean. There's nothing you own that you can get by
stealing from others. It's
not a proper thing to do.  To
keep it in your home,
we should teach those things,
like clean karma.
Those karmic actions, those impure actions,
should do things
that are quite interesting.
Don't
forget to arrange those
interesting things in your next life. In
your next life, be
generous, as that is the motivation so that
in the next life I have
wonderful things to give to
others. Finally,
I have found wonderful things in
my next life, and
I will continue to give, and in the
end, we will
be now. Lord, it is...  I mean,
you have to do the same things, the
same steps with
your good seeds. It's very
interesting, very interesting.
Every time you meditate,
when you finish meditating,
practice giving away
good seeds, just like we did
today. It's like
sunlight. Can you give away
good seeds? It's
very good to pretend.
Can you give me your
good seeds? If so, can you
teach others to give away
their good seeds and give away
good living in that way? If
so, when he said, "Don't
control who
says that," there are two ways to answer. One is,
I'll make a bet of
$100 for whoever answers correctly. But
the other is, I
won't make a bet, but you
answered so well that I have to give you $100. So,
what should this outburst of anger be done to, and what should it be directed at?
100 dollars, raise your hand. So
what should we do with this anger? Exactly
what object are we
talking about?
Anger destroys all the
good seeds, and it's not good to dedicate them to
future seeds, to a
very good future life. 100 dollars,
your good seeds, they will no longer
belong to you. Oh my god, it's very
serious. Here, I will... I don't
care about giving away
my car, but my good seeds... all the
things you promised, you gave away
everything. Even
your good seeds, the
seeds in your mind, they no
longer belong to you, they
belong to others. You have
a
responsibility not to harm anything, those are the
seeds in your mind, the
way to destroy the
bad seeds, the
good seeds in your mind, that is
anger. You need to avoid
anger because those seeds... those
things...  It will break
your good seeds,
and you won't have
those good seeds anymore. It's no longer up to you, woman.
You have no right, you have no
right to be angry because you don't have
ownership, you don't have the right to
break your good seeds
in your heart because you will give
it, you will have to give it,
it's quite difficult. We're almost
finished. The final part
here is also
about your moral responsibilities. It's not
just about protecting the seeds you
have, but it's more than that. It's
your moral responsibility that
when you use money for
others, you give money to
others, but you don't just give
them the money. It's your responsibility to
invest and earn more profit and
give more money away. Like, you
have money, I keep about $10,000
for a tour in Latin America
and
[music],
and my friend and I should give that
money.  That today, and
but I should have more
interest here that I should
transfer, I should transfer that amount of money, I'm
transferring 11, for example. It's your responsibility to
transfer more than what you
committed. You have interest, the
extra interest,
like now it's $100, and
then I'll be silent, and I'll go
there, and I'll thank you. So,
finally, how do you add
interest to
your spiritual seeds? I'll give you
$100, $100. You have to say those
things. By the
way, in the next retreat you
come to,
try to be the one who keeps the box. So you can,
you can have a box.
Okay, you can bring a fake box.
I'll have two boxes
here. This woman said to purify all the
parts of the
mind or
spiritual seeds. I don't own one.
It's like everything I have
I've dedicated to others,
but I'm just keeping it, but
I'm transferring it, and I'm giving more Buddha back to
it. Instead of giving away $10,000
for that tour, I could transfer
$11,000. And if I invest, I invest
more in that part more intelligently,
more wisely, I will get
more. I will get 100 more
good seeds, hundreds of
good seeds more
easily. The
woman replied, "Coffee meditation," the
man replied, "
Enjoying coffee meditation." Oh, $100?
Okay, let's transfer more
seeds. You promised that it's a
very good thing. When people ask me
for advice on this matter,
when you borrow money, and then
in the business of about
10 minutes, right? You borrow $100,000,
you
promise
100,000, that's it.  If $10,000 comes
back, you can add
more and more, you can add even more than that amount.